Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.2. General Classification (200)
    - 209.08 Philosophy--Evolution
      - Darwin's Theory of Conscience (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Ethical Evolution of Mankind (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Kidd's Social Evolution (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Sutherland – Moral Instincts (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Morals in Evolution – Hobhouse (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Weak Points in Evolution theory (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Darwin’s Theory (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Huxley – Evolution and Ethics (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Concerning Evolution (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Bergson’s “Creative Evolution” (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Scopes Trial (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Memo. – evolutionary theory (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 209.09 Philosophy--Spinoza (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 209.09 Philosophy--Logic
      - Sigwart (note in German) (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Logic (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Sigwart (Methods of Ethics) (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Sellars (Essentials of Logic) (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Notes on Logic (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Robinson (The Principles of Reasoning) (Box 45, Folder 1a)
      - Irrationalism (Box 45, Folder 1a)
    - 209.10 Philosophy--Philosophy Club Notes (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 210 Theology and Theologians
      - Luther (Martin) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Augustine (Saint)
        - Confessions (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Encheiridion ad Laurentium (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - De Civitate Dei (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Origen and St. A. (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - St. Augustine (Folder 2)
          - (Heberweg) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (L. Bertrand) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (Pelagius) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (Harnack) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (Britannica) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (Enc.Rel. & Eth.) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (Smith & Wace) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (notes on) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - (A preliminary note) (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - Nature and grace (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - Conception of immortality (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 210.01 Theology and Theologians--Catholic Church
      - Movements within the (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Catechism (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Christian History (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Jesuits (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Spiritual Exercises of Loyola (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Jottings (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Secret of the Jesuits (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Power and secret of the Jesuits (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Dominicans (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Different religious denominations (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The virginity of Mary (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Jesuit order (Huber) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - “Jesuits” (Britannica) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Theophilanthropie (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Franciscans and Dominicans (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Rosary (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Inquisition (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Immaculate Conception (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Transubstantiation (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Bonaventure Mysticism (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - “Heaven" in the Cath. Enc. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Christian History (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Sabatier (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Thomas a Kempis (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - La Trappe & Pythagoras (Silence) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Purification from Sin as an Element of Worship (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Notes (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Current Happenings (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Purgatory (Cath. Ency.) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Saints as persecutors (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Newman's Apologia - notes (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Imitation of Christ (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Imitation of Christ [1932] (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Pope's Encyclica1 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - In extremis (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Eastern Church (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Sacraments (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Modern Saint (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Catholic School Question (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Philosophy of the Cenontists (Political) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Newman’s Apologia (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Jesuits (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Thomas a Kempis (Imitation) & add. notes (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Sin and Penitence (Cath Ency) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Hildebrandt’s Aim (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Popes (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Inquisition (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - R.C. Church (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Papacy (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Father Damian (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Breviary (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 210.02 Theology and Theologians (Miscellaneous)
      - Inge--“On the State” (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Inge's Outspoken Essays (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Fosdick--“The Meaning of Faith" (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Analogy of religion (Butler) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Thomas Aquinas (notes) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - New Infinite and Old Theology (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Doctrine of Sin (Mueller) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Sin (Herzog) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Justification by Faith (Herzog) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Agnosticism (Enc. Brit) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - St. Anselm and the Ontological Argument (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Butler's Analogy (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Theosophy (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Oxford Reformers (Seebohm) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Thomas Aquinas (Dunning) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Anselmus of Canterbury (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Relation of Holiness to Perfection (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Inge's Plotinus (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Repugnance of Dogmatism to Religion (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Cathari (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - A problem of religious history (The appearance of monotheism) - Adler (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Notes for a critique of monotheistic religion (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 210.03 Theology and Theologians--Christian Subjects
      - Church and State (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Saint Paul's mysticism (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Faith, hope and charity (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Kautsky's "Origin of Christianity" (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - The Lord's Prayer (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - "Why has Christianity failed?" (Union Seminary) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - "Thy will be done" (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - History of Christianity in the Light of Modern Knowledge (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Christianity (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Note-Sunday Talk (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Christian Missions-Dennis (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Christianity at the Crossroads-Tyrell (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Note-Evening Talk (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Imitation of Christ-McGiffert (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Paul’s Doctrine of Faith (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Paul’s Body of Death (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Moravians (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Notes on the Kingdom of Heaven (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - "What is Christianity" - Fosdick (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Sketch of a Treatise on the Christian (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Principle of Love (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Calvin (Geneva) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Calvin, the Will of God (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Parallel between St. Augustine &: Calvin (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - The Institutes' of Calvin (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Walker's Life of Calvin (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Difference between Pagan and Hebrew-Christian view of Life (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Liberal Christianity (note for address) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Christian Principle of Love (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Hebrew and Christian Tradition (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Parables of Jesus (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Fosdick – Modern Use of Bible (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Calvin (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 210.04 Theology and Theologians--Ibn Pahya (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 210.05 Theology and Theologians--Ethical Religion
      - (Notes of Addresses) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 210.06 Theology and Theologians--Religion--General (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Stream of consciousness (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The imagery used by religions (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Predispositions for certain types (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - of religion (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Religion - Hebrew &: Christian compared (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Nash's lecture (religious ideal) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The study of religions (Peekskill notes) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Tragic aspect of life (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Notes on religion (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Changes in Men’s Ideas about God (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Self-knowledge – Religion (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Pleas for Religious Conformance (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Church and State (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - James – Varieties of Religious experience (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Jastrow – The Study of Religion (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Facing the Religious Situation (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Miller – Sin (Vol. 1) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The sense of Sin (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The Constitute Elements of Religion (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 210.07 Theology and Theologians--Non-Christian Religions
      - The Doctor's Thesis on Lau-Tzi (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Professor Asawaka's Paper on Bushido (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Life of Buddha (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Brahma (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Points in conversation with M. Jastrow (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Collateral reading (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Islam (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Pischen’s Book (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - De la Sausays (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Jastrow (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Pilgrimages (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Notes – Zoroaster, Mohammed, the Avesta (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - India (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Duncker’s Chapters (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Buddha (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Vendidad (Box 46, Folder 1a)
        - Brahmanism (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Peruvian Religion – Reville (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Japan – Yokoi’s Art, Lafcadio Hearn – Count Okuma (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - China – Lao-tse (Box 46, Folder 1a)
      - Tyranny of decisive moments (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Oldenberg’s Buddha (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Buddhist Birth Stories (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - The Buddhistic Attitude and My Own Comparison Between Source of Conception of Hell·in Hindu, Persian and Christian Religions (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Primitive Religion (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Ketcham - Ethics of Islam (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Extracts from the Koran· (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Japan article in the E.B. (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Islam (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Buddhism (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Taoism (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Mormonism (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Eleusinian Mysteries (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Wells’ Outlines - Buddhism (Box 46, Folder 1b)
      - Mohammedanism (Box 46, Folder 1b)
    - 211 Greek and Roman Classics
      - Platonic Idea of the Two Halves (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Notes on the Odyssey (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Letters of Seneca (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Bible of the Greeks (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Poem of the Iliad (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Impressions of the Odyssey (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Boethius (De consolatione) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Roman literature - Seneca (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Seneca (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Seneca (Friedlander) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Seneca - Rene waltz (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Chapman's Homer (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Homer (3) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Impressions of the Odyssey (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The Iliad (3) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The Argument of the Phaedon (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The Odyssey (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - The Iliad (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Seneca on Anger etc. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Tacitus- Annals, Agricola, "Oratory" (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Boethius (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - "Peric1es and Aspasia" - Landor (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Isocrates (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Bust of Epicurus (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Froude 's Caesar (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Roman literature (Crutwell) (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Roman literature (Varro) (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Antigone (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - P1utarch's lives (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Caesar (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Homer and Virgil (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Plutarch's "Isis and Osiris" (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Caesar’s Commentaries (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Demeter – The Eleusinian Mysteries and the Orpheus Cult (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Four Cardinal Virtues of the Greeks (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Life in Ancient Athens (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Young Greek Athlete in the Museum (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - The Historian (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Pericles Funeral Oration (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Letter – Pliny to Calpurnia (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Notes – Greek Religion (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Roman Literature (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Solon (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Tyrtaeos (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Kallinos (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Euripides’ Hippolytus (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Readings from Herodotus (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Aristophanes – Clouds (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Cicero’s Letters (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Bimillenary Anniversary of Virgil’s Birthday (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Cicero – De Officiis (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Sophocles tragedies (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Remarks on “Oedipus at Colonus” (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Comments on the Aeneid (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - General Notes (Virgil) (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Pericles (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Course of lectures for next year (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Aeschylus (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Virgil’s Aeneid (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - The Virgil celebration (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Euripides (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Virgil – Georgics (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Aeschuylus – Prometheus Bound (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Iphigenia in Aluis (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Mimnermos (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Sophocles – Oedipus, Oedipus Rex, Philoctetes, Oedipus at Colonus (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Pericles (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Pindar – 1st Olympic Ode (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Greek Mythology (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Herodotus (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Cicero – Friendship and Old Age (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Aeneid (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Pity and Terror (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 212 Miscellaneous (Unclassified)
      - Embroiderers of Vosges and Building Societies
        - The Makers of Steel Instruments in the Factory of Hermioncourt (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - The Embroiderers of Vosges (40pp.) (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Building Societies (44pp.) (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Commerce
        - Day’s History of Commerce (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Notes on commerce (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - First sketch of commerce lecture (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Notes on commercial morality (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Notes of Cal. Univ. lecture, 1907 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - The Standard
        - (Also note on “Ethical Record”) (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Policy for The Standard (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Proposed English edition (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Memo on The Standard (3) (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Foreign Language Studies
        - Croft’s German Series (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Vaughan's Poem (trans.) (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - German locutions (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Memo (Luther's treatise) (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Peculiarities of Latin language (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - French Locutions (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Translation into French (Ghost Story) (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Translation in German (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - 213 Biographical
      - Thomas Carlyle (Folder 1)
        - Notes on Carlyle (4) (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Fitch's Carlyle's “Cromwell” (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Firth - Cromwell (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Memo for the Cromwell Paper (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Notes on “letters of Cromwell”, “Sartor Resartus,” etc. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Rousseau (Folder 2)
        - Rousseau’s Social Contract (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Rousseau’s “The origin of inequality…” (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Rousseau’s “Democracy and representation” (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Rousseau’s Idea of freedom (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Biographical Notes
        - Carl Schurz (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Lincoln (Letters and Addresses) (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Adams (Henry), The Education of (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Cromwell (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Renan (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Manning (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Rabelais (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Ballin (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Philips Brooks (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Newton, Galileo, Byron (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Matthew Arnold
        - Matthew Arnold as a guide in religion (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Arnold: Literature and dogma (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Arnold: Essay, "Literature and science" (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Arnold: Culture and Anarchy (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Matthew Arnold's Philosophy of Life (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Emerson
        - Emerson's essay on "Compensation" (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Emerson's essay on "History" (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - "The heart of Emerson's Journal" (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Emerson's "Wood notes" (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Emerson's essay on "Self-reliance" (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Notes on Emerson (7) (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - ''Emerson'' (100th birthday) (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 213.01 Biographical--Character Studies (Polarities or Inconcinnities)
      - Caesar Augustus (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Polarities of Character (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Wolsey, More, Cranmer, Henry VIII (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - St. Bernard (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Campanella (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - More (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Abelard (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Athanasius (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Berlioz (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Clemenceau (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Voltaire (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Adler (Dr. I.) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Oliver Cromwell (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Richelieu (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Johnson (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Copernicus (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Bruno, Campanella, Kepler (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Alexander the Great (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Caesar (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - General Reflections (13 pp.) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Bret Harte (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Tiberius (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Bodin, Althusius, Jacob Boehme (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Pasteur (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - John Stuart Mill (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Sir Philip Sydney (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Lasalle (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Ivan the Terrible (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Gibbon (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Carlyle (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Las Casas (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - ''Eminent Victorians" -Strachey (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Montesquieu, Fouche, Napoleon, Philippe-Egalite (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Samuel Johnson (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Men and Art of the Renaissance (Swaitchick) Petrarch, Da Feltre, Mirondola, De Medici, Fra Angelico, Donatello (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Remarks on the General Plan of Character Study (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Columbus (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Denosthenes (2) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Jero (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Seneca (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Goethe (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Types of Reformers (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - X. (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - John Chrysostom (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Constantine (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Abraham Geiger (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Paul Gerhard (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Julian the Apostate (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Leonardo (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Stewardson (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Winckelman (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The Abbot of Cluny (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - John Milton (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Robert Browning (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - George Elliott (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Martin Luther (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Jene Welsh (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Saint Theresa (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Henrik Ibsen (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Gaodstone (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Robert Southey (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Erasmus (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Renan, Nietzsche, Carlyle (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Paracelsus (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Wagner (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - St. Jerome (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Swedenborg (2) (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Gustav Werner (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - St. Francis of Assisi (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - St. Francis of Sales (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Catherine II, Germany (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Napoleon (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Vittoria Colonna and Michael Angelo (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Milton (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Richelieu (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Catherine of Siena (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Catherine de Medici (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Pythagoras (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Jefferson (3) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Huxley (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Descartes (2) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Burke (2) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Robespierre, Gensonne (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - General Armstrong (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Keppler, Calilei (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Mme. Roland (2) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Chatham (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Bayard (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Notes on Persons (Hil1quit) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Hu Su (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Dr. I Adler (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Golding (2) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Steinthal (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Hoover (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Lincoln (4) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Frothingham (2) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Mrs. P (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - The Elder Cato (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Uses of Biography in the Home (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Leading Traits (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Additional biographical studies (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Additional note on biography (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Concentration (re: biography) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Li Hung Chang (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Carl Barnes, Prof Zueblin, Moskowitz, Mr. Gill (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Salter (3) (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Jeanne d’Arc (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Lord Shaftsbury (2) (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Jacob Riis (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Gandhi (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - John M. (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Pupin (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Montaigne and Stevenson (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - K. (2) (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Machiavelli (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Canning (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - President Hayes (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - H.S. (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Mme. Roland (2) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Galilei (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Tagore (2) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Robespierre (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Goethe and Plato (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Mr. Noyes (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Saladin (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Mr. Baillie (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Bismarck (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Mr. Munson (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Buddha (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Savonarola (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Frederick the Great (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Caroline T. Haven (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - 214 Jewish Subjects
      - Universalism as related to legalism (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - "Eili, Eili" (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Zionism - notes (Atlantic City) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - A line of thought· apropos of Zionism (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Jewish Religion (Sombart) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Legends of the Jews (Ginsberg) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Religion of the Semites (Robertson Smith) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Rise of Hebrew Monotheism (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Disappointment of the Jew, as compared with that of the Christian (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Zionism (3) (Box 47, Folder 1)